

11935 Travis Path San Antonio, TX 78253 210.278.8717

kriscates81@gmail.com

Twitter: @kriscates81 GitHub: kcates81

# **Summary Statement**

Entry-level LAMP+J Developer transitioning from a 10+ year career in proposal/project management and business development. Particularly interested in using back-end languages to solve problems for businesses and end-users. Currently adding functionality to personal website using Laravel and watching Laracasts to deepen understanding of PHP and the Laravel framework.

### **Skills**

Front-End Technologies		Back-End Technologies	Other Tools
HTML 5	Mailgun API	PHP	GitHub
CSS 3		MySQL	Trello
JavaScript		Laravel 4.2	Vagrant VM
jQuery		SequelPro	
Twitter Bootstrap CSS			
Materialize CSS			
Google Maps API			
Open Weather Maps API			
Tiny MCE Text Editor			

# **Projects**

### **Major Projects**

#### FLIT | Laravel 4.2, MySQL, SequelPro, Materialize CSS, Mailgun API, Stripe API

My team and I have developed an application that allows freelancers to track their projects and outstanding invoices using the Laravel framework. This application allows users to create an account, projects, and clients and track project and invoice deadlines. Users can view their information in a high-level dashboard view or in detailed page views. The hallmarks of this project are simplistic design, intuitive information architecture, and modular, easily-maintainable code.

Blog Project | Laravel 4.2, MySQL, SequelPro, jQuery, Tiny MCE Text Editor, Materialize CSS, HTML, CSS, GitHub Developed and deployed a personal website and blog from scratch using the Laravel 4.2 framework.

## Adlister Project | PHP, MySQL, SequelPro, HTML, CSS, Materialize CSS, Trello, GitHub

Worked with two other classmates to develop a Craigslist clone using PHP and MySQL (SequelPro). Used Trello as a project management tool to develop all tasks and related activities, assign responsibilities and due dates, and communicate project status. Also, first experience forking, branching, pulling, and merging code as part of a team in GitHub.

# **Additional Projects**

# Whack-a-Mole | jQuery, HTML, CSS, Twitter Bootstrap, GitHub

Built a simple whack-a-mole game using jQuery. The application generates a random mole and associates that mole the ID of a div within HTML. The application checks the user's clicks against the random mole displayed. It also keeps score, remembers the high score, and keeps a game timer.

# Simple Simon | ¡Query, HTML, CSS, Twitter Bootstrap, GitHub

Built a game based off of the classic Simon toy. Used jQuery to randomly loop through an array of colored squares, check the user clicks against the randomly selected squares, and determine whether the user can continue to play or if they have lost.

Weather Map API | JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Materialize CSS, Google Maps API, Open Weather Map API, GitHub Built a weather application that gives the 5-day forecast for any location. Built using jQuery, the Google Maps API, and the Open Weather Map API. This application allows users to enter the latitude and longitude for any location to update the weather. Users can also drag and drop the location marker within the map to update the forecast.

11935 Travis Path San Antonio, TX 78253 210.278.8717

#### kriscates81@gmail.com

Twitter: @kriscates81 GitHub: kcates81

## National Parks Listing | PHP, MySQL, SequelPro, Materialize CSS, HTML, CSS, GitHub

Built a listing of national park using PHP and MySQL. Also built a form that allows users to add parks to the database and display them on the page

#### Calculator | JavaScript, Twitter Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, GitHub

Used JavaScript to build a basic calculator application that performs addition, subtraction, multiplication, and division. Also allows for decimals and negative numbers.

### **Education and Certifications**

# 2016 | Codeup

16-week Immersive learning program that teaches the LAMP+J stack

# 2012 | Villanova University

Government Contract Management Certificate Program

# 2011 | Project Management Professional (PMP) Certification, Project Management Institute

PMP Number: 1450942

# 2003 | Salisbury University

Bachelor of Arts - English

## **Additional Training:**

- PMI Project Management Professional Certification Training, Spring Forward, 2011
- Capturing Federal Business Training, Shipley Associates, 2011
- Winning Federal Business Training, Shipley Associates, 2008
- Winning Proposal Strategies and Winning Executive Summaries Training, Shipley Associates, 2005

# **Previous Work Experience**

### December 2012 - March 2016 | Professional Performance Development Group, Inc.

#### Proposal Writer/Coordinator

Managed the proposal process for a government contractor that provides medical staff to military treatment facilities across the United States and its territories. In this position, I managed cross-functional teams to design solutions to meet client needs and develop responsive proposals. Member of the Strategic Planning Committee representing the Business Development department. This team was tasked with developing a 3-year strategic plan for the company including, mission and vision, strategic themes, and strategic initiatives. Managed proposal for corporate VA 621I Federal Supply Schedule contract vehicle renewal. Managed winning proposals for SeaPort-e multiple award contract, US Air Force 711th Human Performance Wing Mission Support Services, and US Army Health Facilities Planning Agency Professional and Administrative Support Services

#### May 2010 - December 2012 | V-Tech Solutions, Inc.

#### Contracts Manager | Capture Manager, Defense and Intelligence Sector | Proposal Specialist

Served as the focal point of contact for all contractual matters; acted as contractual authority among company, customers, and subcontracting partners alike. Coordinated the preparation of offers for GSA IT-70 and MOBIS multiple-award schedules. Identified opportunities within Federal defense and intelligence agencies by leveraging agency forecasts, FedBizzOpps, and other online business development applications. Gathered intelligence about Federal defense and intelligence agencies through Web, print, audio, and social media as well as analyzing agency strategic plans and attending government OSDBU outreaches and vendor days. Managed the proposal process; includes analyzing RFP/RFQ documents, preparing schedules, templates, and outlines, facilitating the review cycle, editing and formatting proposal documents, and producing the final proposal package for submission to the client.

March 2007 - January 2010 | Aquilent, Inc. | Proposal Specialist September 2004 - February 2007 | Allegis Group Services, Inc. | Proposal Writer